[ethereal music playing]
[♪♪♪]
For the glory of the Sources.
[bushes rustling]
Greetings, traveler.
[Chief Loyalist] This is it?
The Shrine of the Seven Sources?
Yes.
Have you come to pay homage
to our humble shrine?
[Chief Loyalist]
"Humble" is right.
I expected something
a little more impressive.
Praise of the Source Dragons
has little to do
with outward displays...
only inner devotion.
[Chief Loyalist]
How very "enlightened" of you.
So, each column
channels the presence
of the power
of one of the Source Dragons?
You've done your research.
As long as a Dragon's energy
flows through the lands,
its column will glow forth
as a tribute.
Sadly,
one of the Source Dragons
has passed,
but one day,
when the cycle renews, all--
[Chief Loyalist] Yes, yes,
yes, "Praise the Sources"
or whatever,
but have you observed
any fluctuations
or anomalies
in the power distribution recently?
Uh...
I'm... I'm sorry,
I... I don't
understand the question.
[Chief Loyalist]
I'm looking for any indication
of--
-[rumbling]
--of that!
[gasping in shock]
[Chief Loyalist]
Ha! Just as I hypothesized.
Source withdrawal.
I'm... I'm sure this outage
is only temporary.
Besides, we still have
five mighty Sources--
[gasping]
No cause for alarm.
There are still a majority--
[gasping in horror]
[crackling and rumbling]
[Acolytes gasping]
[Acolyte] A majority of Sources
have removed their power
from the lands?
Great Dragons, why have you
forsaken us mortals?
[gasping]
[bubbling]
[snarling]
[roaring]
[Acolytes screaming]
[monsters roaring]
[roaring]
[acid hissing]
[screaming]
[Chief Loyalist] As predicted,
the manifestations
have already begun.
The foolish Ninja have played
right into our hands.
The quest for Desolation
begins now.
[screaming]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪
[Lloyd]
He was called "ThunderFang,
the Shatter Dragon of Chaos."
[Arin]
Scary name, scary dragon.
Also long name, long dragon.
Only way to beat him?
Summon ThunderFang's
old nemesis,
the Arc Dragon of Focus.
[Lloyd] Classic matchup,
Chaos versus Focus,
but ThunderFang
was so powered up,
the Focus Dragon
couldn't do it alone.
[Arin]
So we helped guide them.
I know it sounds unbelievable,
but our minds were, like,
sharing a dragon's brain!
[Lloyd]
With the Focus Dragon's help,
we beat ThunderFang for good.
World saved!
[Arin]
But some of the Source Dragons
might not be happy with us
for summoning that Arc Dragon
without their permission.
[Lloyd] So, we were heading
back to Ninjago
when I felt something weird
going on with my powers.
Then we went though
the portal gate--
And it spat us out here.
Wherever "here" is,
it's obviously not home,
so we tried to go back
through the portal--
And it wouldn't work.
Totally inactive,
but how are you here?
Basically same?
Minus the dragon
mind-brain thing.
I was in the Cloud Kingdom,
felt my Powers going weird.
I wanted to ask
you Ninja about it, but...
when I went through the gate,
it sent me here.
Sorry you got stranded too,
but it's nice to see you again.
So you have no idea
what happened?
To our powers
or the Portal Gates?
[Lloyd] No idea.
Let's check out
the neighborhood.
It might have some answers.
[Arin] Wow...
It's beautiful.
You Cloud Monks record stuff
about all the lands, right?
Any idea where we are?
My focus is the Wyldness's
late medieval period.
I've never seen anything
quite like this place.
Me neither.
Hopefully the other Ninja
aren't having
the same problems we are.
[Nya] This is not Ninjago.
We needed to get back
to Ninjago.
Why is the Portal Gate
malfunctioning?
[Kai] What's also weird?
When we left Mysterium,
it was day.
Now it's
the middle of the night.
[Jay] A cloudy night.
No moons, no stars.
[Kai] A fireball
should light things up.
[spluttering]
Oh, yeah, guess what.
Elemental Powers
are also on the fritz.
Hold on, let me try this.
H'yah!
[groaning]
[laughing]
I was feeling bummed
about our powers
not working right,
but that made me feel
a little better.
I'll remember this
when you end up
zapping yourself
with a giant lightning storm.
Nya, can't you get
the Portal Gate going again?
[Nya] Get it going how?
It's powered down.
We don't even know
how or why it spat us out here.
Um...
Take us to Ninjago!
See? Nothing.
Looks like we have to
find another way
back to Ninjago.
I say we wait till sun-up
so we can see where we are,
then take it from there.
[smashing]
Hey, Kai, we're gonna need
a campfire.
Think you could, um...
[scoffing] Of course I can.
Hah! H'yah!
You set him up for that
on purpose,
didn't you?
-[shrugging] Hmm.
[Sora] Portal Gates are usually
in monasteries,
and I don't see a monastery
around here,
unless--
[Wyldfyre grunting]
Come on, come on!
If I can't blast fireballs,
who even am I?
[Frak] Wait...
Feel that?
Like a little tremor?
You felt that, right?
[Riyu grumbling negatively]
[groaning] You're right.
Who am I kidding?
There was no tremor!
If I can't quake, what'll I do?
What am I even good for?
Your powers aren't
what give you your worth.
Of course they are!
Yeah, what are you
talking about, Sora?
Please freak out like us.
I was solving problems
long before I had
an Elemental Power.
And this is a problem.
I mean,
the portal gate spit us out
in some random, unknown spot?
Why?
And our powers.
Don't forget
our powers problem.
Kai will know what's going on.
We need to get back to Ninjago.
Yeah,
but without a working
Portal Gate,
looks like we're walking.
And in which direction?
And...
Wait.
It's dawn everywhere.
So, this kinda makes
knowing what direction to go
a little hard, right?
A little.
[stomach grumbling]
I can hear
your stomachs growling.
I've got these wafers left.
It wasn't my stomach, for once.
Not me either.
Plus, I'd rather starve
than eat those.
What's with
the miserable faces?
It's not like this is
the first time
we've been stuck
in some unknown place.
Remember the Never-Realm?
Or in Prime Empire, when...
Oh...
right.
You don't remember any of that.
No, I don't.
Back in the City of Temples,
do you know why I left?
We hadn't paid you yet?
No!
I was watching you all,
the way you worked together,
more like a family
than a team...
a family I had no memory of,
and that made me feel
more lonely than I'd ever felt.
I had to get away.
But as soon as I was gone,
I regretted it.
especially after
what you said to me, Nya.
I don't know if you'll ever
get those memories back, Jay,
but we're together now.
We can build new memories.
But that's just it.
The more time I spend with you,
I realize...
I need more than new memories.
I need to remember
the first time we met.
The first time we danced.
The first time
I made you smile.
Those memories
can't be gone forever.
They have to be somewhere
in your mind.
We just have to find a way
to bring them back.
[bird tweeting]
[♪♪♪]
[birds chirping, music playing]
[low rumbling]
Zane, are you okay?
I'm not sure, Pixal.
I feel... off.
My powers... are gone?
[spluttering]
[yelping] Ah!
[birds retreating,
chirping in alarm]
Something's very wrong.
I've gotta find the other Ninja.
There are plenty
of worse places
to get stranded, I guess,
and after everything
we've been through,
I'm cool with a little peace.
Yeah, this is
the exact opposite
of fighting undead dragons.
Or crawling through
the Underworld.
You went to the Underworld?
I feel like
Ras dragged me everywhere.
Ras?
That tiger guy that attacked
the Cloud Kingdom?
Who talks all--
"No one will stop me,
I'm so mean, roar-roar"
and stuff?
[chuckling] Yeah.
A lot's happened since we last
hung out, Euphrasia.
I even stupidly
left the Ninja team.
You did what you thought
you needed to do, Arin.
I was so caught up
in other problems,
I should have seen
what you were going through.
You have
so many responsibilities,
I don't blame you
for that, Lloyd.
I should have been the one
to teach you proper Spinjitzu.
Ras showed me
how to do that, yes,
but I'm not sure
it was the best way.
He... exploited my anger.
I can't believe you have
an angry bone in your body.
I was mad at Master Wu
for causing the Merge.
I blamed him for the death
of my parents,
but my parents were still alive.
I should never
have trusted Ras.
Master Wu caused the Merge?
Why?
You have no idea
how badly I wish I knew
the answer to that question.
[wind gusting, faint whispering]
You hear that?
Is someone there?
[disembodied whispering]
Odd.
[wind gusting]
[whispers swirling]
Okay, a little bit creepy.
Maybe a lot a bit creepy.
[woodland birds,
disembodied whispering]
Is someone following us?
We don't even know
if anyone lives here.
We haven't seen any trails,
not even footprints.
[disembodied whispering]
Could the trees be whispering?
[whispers swirling and growing]
Follow the whispers!
[Frak] ...and that's why
we should obviously
head that way,
toward those large,
pleasant trees.
But I hear running water
over there.
I'm sure it's clean
and refreshing,
and unless you brought
a hose or a camel,
we're going to need some.
No, we need to get
to the Monastery of Ninjago,
not to trees or water.
As the most accomplished
Ninja here,
I think we--
Most accomplished Ninja?
Most accomplished at what,
being annoying?
I'll be leading
this little group,
thank you very much.
[Wyldfyre chuckling]
Listen, before he died,
Egalt, one of the greatest
dragons to ever live,
told me...
-[Riyu sniffing air]
I'd be a leader someday.
I'm thinking that day is today.
No offense to Egalt,
but even great masters
get things wrong sometimes.
[Frak] And that
doesn't change the fact
that I was studying the Ninja
before either of you
even heard of Spinjitzu.
Really?
Was that
when you were working for Ras?
You worked for him
after I did.
[Sora] I was hanging with Arin.
Ras just happened to be there.
[Frak] You still did
what Ras said.
[Sora groaning]
[Cole] Hello?
Anyone?
The place is empty.
Last I remember,
something invisible attacked me,
then I woke up here.
You were in Spectral Sleep,
and I was so focused
on trying to save you,
I made some stupid mistakes
and got my soul drained, too.
I just hope Kai and the others
pulled through.
[gasping]
Make sure you keep
her healing leaves warm
with your hands.
That's how
my grandmother did it.
Oh, no, what happened here?
[Geo] Ras happened.
Are you okay?
I'll be fine,
but I don't know
about Rontu there.
[groaning]
What did Ras come here for?
No clue.
He forced me
to take him
to Master Wu's old study,
and I think he took something,
but I don't know what,
or why.
Then he left
through the Portal Gate.
Whatever Ras is up to,
it can't be good.
It never is.
[disembodied whispers swirling]
Where is this taking us?
[distant shrieking and roaring]
That sounds bad.
[beings shrieking]
[roaring]
[shrieking]
[Euphrasia gasping]
What are those things?
No idea,
but you thinking
what I'm thinking?
[Lloyd] Ninja... go!
[smacking]
[grunting with effort]
Ugh, this is the worst!
[roaring]
[Lloyd groaning]
[Euphrasia straining,
wind gusting]
[powers spluttering]
Oh! Uh, sorry!
Accident!
[chuckling awkwardly]
I'm usually better at that!
[Arin] These are the weirdest
Elemental Masters
I've ever seen.
[Lloyd] I don't think
they're masters.
I think they're actually
made of Elemental Powers.
[snapping claws]
[Arin] What?
How is that even possible?
[Lloyd] Don't ask me.
Wu didn't prepare me
for anything like this!
[roaring]
Oh! Uh...
Never used one of these before,
but, uh...
[acid hissing]
[roaring]
Uh-oh.
H'ah!
[roaring]
Ah!
[Arin] Get to safety!
[grunting with effort] H'yah!
[acid hissing]
[monster screeching]
[Lloyd struggling]
[Lloyd] No!
[disembodied whispering]
What the...?
[whispers swirling]
[bursting and sparking]
[♪♪♪]
H'yah!
H'ah! H'yah!
[♪♪♪]
[Arin]
Lloyd got his powers working?
[gasping] I'm back too!
[♪♪♪]
[monster groaning]
[sparking and crackling]
Uh... did we... destroy them?
[sighing] Not sure.
If they're pure Elemental power,
they may have just...
changed to another form.
[sparking and spluttering]
Aw, no!
[groaning] Come on.
[sighing] Too good to last.
Can I just say,
this place might be beautiful,
but it is weird!
[beings chittering
and squeaking]
[Euphrasia laughing]
Guess they're happy
we saved them?
[chittering]
[Arin] Follow them?
Don't have any better ideas.
[beings chittering]
Weird, but cute.
[wind gusting]
[Riyu sniffing and snuffling]
[grumbling and sniffing]
Another reason
I should be the leader?
If it wasn't for me,
we'd still be fighting that...
[nervously] ...puppet
in the desert.
You stop one puppet,
and you think
that makes you our leader?
It was a big puppet!
Man, all this walking
has made me thirsty.
Then you should've listened
when I suggested
we follow the sound
of running water!
Looks like we don't need to.
[Sora] How did we
not see that before?
Who cares? [sighing]
You're right about one thing,
all this walking...
[slurping]
...I could use a rest.
Hmm, perfect!
What are the chances?
[stomach growling]
Oh, wish we brought some food.
I could use a Wyldmelon
right about now.
[Arin] Okay,
so, thinking this through,
both of your Elemental Powers
are acting strange,
`
the Portal Gates aren't working,
and monsters that look like
pure Elemental Energy show up.
[Euphrasia]
You think it's all related?
It's a good question,
and how did these trees
give me my powers back,
at least for a little while?
I didn't get a tree blast
like you did,
but mine still came back.
[Lloyd] I hope these little guys
are leading us to some answers.
[deep rumbling]
[♪♪♪]
[groaning]
[heaving and rumbling]
[beings chittering]
[gasping in awe] Wow...
[disembodied whispering,
wind gusting]
Whoa...
Is that a Source Dragon?
I... don't think so?
[rumbling and stretching]
[Arin quietly]
Are we supposed to say hi?
Greetings, mighty dragon.
My name is--
[Arc Dragon, telepathically]
I know who you are,
Lloyd, Son of Garmadon.
My trees sensed
the Elemental Master of Life
the moment you arrived
in our wood,
and sent their whispers to me.
We had long given up
on the Legendary Green Ninja
ever returning to us.
Returned?
[annoyed] For generations,
the Protector
of the Whispering Wood
has performed their duties,
but you are the first
who ignored those duties,
and we have long felt betrayed.
What...?
[roaring mightily]
[Chief Loyalist] ...and so,
all I've hypothesized
has been proven.
Without realizing it,
our enemies have
inadvertently set in motion
their own downfall,
and our restoration.
The energy manifestations
have already begun.
[Loyalists applauding]
[Loyalist #1]
Ha! A triumph!
[Loyalist #2]
But these creatures,
what do they want?
[Chief Loyalist] Want?
Why, nothing.
They are beings of rage
and destruction
born from the imbalance
of Source Energy,
as manifested by the Weapon.
If we backtrace a manifestation,
we'll find the origin point,
the location
of the Weapon of Desolation.
[Loyalists applauding
and laughing] Well done! Yes!
[Chief Loyalist] Now, go.
Search your assigned regions!
Find the Weapon!
Let nothing stand in your way!
Her time
will finally come again.
[♪♪♪]